It happened on the 29th of April, the first day of Golden Week.
Basically, my mother's husband's second wife is my current "mother,"
and her second husband is my current "father."
So in short, your current parents aren't really your parents at all... right?
But isn't that something you wouldn't normally tell a kid?
My parents are rather frank, so I heard about it before elementary school.
I must really be a burden.
They apparently wanted to send me to an orphanage, but didn't, to save face.
That's why I tried to be a good kid.
Though really, a good kid is just a normal kid, I guess.
When your family situation is so complex, there are times when people are biased against you.
But I decided that I wouldn't change simply because of trivial things like that.
Hanekawa...
What are you planning to do, Araragi-kun?
I mean, it's Golden Week, after all. Aren't you going to study or something?
Why should I have to study during Golden Week?
Well, I like to take walks on days off,
because I don't want to be at home.
Spending a whole day at home with my parents...
freaks me out.
That's why I take walks on days off.
I think you're worrying too much... but okay.
Hey, what's with the gauze on your face?
Do you promise not to tell anyone?
I... promise.
This morning, my father hit me.
Hit you? That's...
Come on, Araragi-kun, think about it.
If you heard an ignorant child talking about something that's none of her business,
you might be a bit annoyed, or get a bit angry...
But isn't that understandable?
No! Violence is understandable?
Are you saying you're okay with that?!
Isn't that the one thing you find most unforgivable?!
It's okay! It's only one time.
You promised, you know, Araragi-kun.
You promised that you wouldn't tell anyone.
But... a promise like that.
Please, Araragi-kun!
Please don't tell anyone about this!
If you don't tell, I'll do anything.
I'm begging you.
Okay, I get it.
What's that?
Will you help me?
Koyomi-oniichan, I've been waiting for you.
Oh, hey there, Sengoku.
What are you doing here?
Koyomi-oniichan, it's just that...
I wanted to thank you properly.
Oh, well if that's it, you should really be thanking Kanbaru instead.
Has she come by here yet?
Yeah, but before I could say anything,
she ran off faster than the eye could see.
She must've had something really important to do. Yeah, that's it.
Yeah... it was like a Lightspeed Attack.
Why would you use the special attack used by Prince Yamato from Bikkuriman to describe her?!
Even worse than being hard to understand, I can't even follow up on the joke without it turning into an explanation!
Yeah...  I didn't expect you to get it.
Koyomi-oniichan, you're as interesting as ever.
But what should I do now?
What's wrong?
Other than talking to Kanbaru-san, I had other things to do, too.
Oh, really?
Yeah...
If that's the case, I'd be more than willing to help out.
I still need to thank Kanbaru-san myself, too.
But I couldn't ask you to do that, Koyomi-oniichan...
I don't mind at all.
I don't consider something like this to be work.
Just leave it to me.
Are you sure? Well, then I guess it's okay...
Here.
This...
It's already been washed.
If you could return it for me, I'd be really grateful.
Well... certainly.
Oh yeah, Sengoku. Can I ask you about something?
What? What is it?
Oh, it's nothing big.
It's about Shinobu.
Shinobu?
Last night after getting rid of the Jagirinawa, we went back to the old school,
and since it was late, we stayed the night, right?
There was a cute little girl with blond hair.
Did she say anything to you while I wasn't there?
No.
I see...
She's a vampire, isn't she?
Yeah, but right now, I guess she's more of a pseudo-vampire.
So it's her fault that you were...
It wasn't her fault. It was mine.
Besides, trying to place the blame on an aberration isn't right.
They're merely trying to exist, and that's just how they are.
Even aberrations have some semblance of reason for the things they do.
That basically sums it up.
Yeah, I guess so.
Well, anyway, don't worry about stuff like that too much.
It'd be best if you just went back to living a normal life.
Yeah.
If you have any problems, feel free to come and talk to me.
Though of course, if you have any really big problems, Oshino may be better able to help.
O-Oh, really?
Yeah, but he did warn me...
I can't just always rely on him.
It's like how if you constantly rely on Doraemon's secret gadgets, you become like Nobita-kun.
Yeah, that's true.
It was Oshino-san that gave you the protective seal, too. That really is like Doraemon's secret gadgets!
It's like the Genius Helmet or Skill Gloves.
Why would you go out of your way to use minor secret gadgets that only showed up in the movies as examples?!
Use something like the Takecopter or the Anywhere Door instead!
Koyomi-oniichan, you always follow up on my jokes perfectly!
W-What is it?
Nothing... really...
I feel like my manhood is being measured when I'm around you.
Don't worry about it.
Oh yeah, Koyomi-oniichan.
What's up?
It's about Shinobu-chan.
Shinobu?
She... was constantly glaring at me.
I feel like her eyes were different when she was looking at you and Oshino-san...
than when she was looking at me and Kanbaru-san.
Are you saying that she looks at men and women differently?
I'm really aware of people's looks... so I can just tell.
Oh, if it isn't Araragi-kun.
What are you doing here?
Umm...
Oh, Hanekawa, this is the girl-
E-E-Excuse me!
Araragi-kun, I think I'm a little hurt.
Umm... yeah, that's my sister's friend that I mentioned yesterday, Sengoku Nadeko.
Oh yeah, Araragi-kun, what happened after that snake incident?
Well, it was basically solved. Though we really just ended up relying on Oshino again.
I don't really understand, but it's good that it was solved swiftly.
Yeah, that's about it.
In any case, she really did seem like a nice, sweet girl.
If I'm not mistaken, that uniform is from the middle school you graduated from, isn't it, Araragi-kun?
You really do know everything, don't you?
It's not that I know everything. I just know what I know.
By the way, Araragi-kun.
What's up?
Didn't you say you had something to do today?
By any chance, was talking to a cute middle school girl the "something" you had to-
No!
That was something concerning Senjougahara.
It's just embarrassing, so I didn't want to say anything.
Senjougahara-san, huh?
Want to hear some interesting rumors?
What? Doesn't sound interesting at all, but I'm listening.
"Ever since Senjougahara became friends with Araragi, she's started acting strangely."
"Araragi is being a bad influence on Senjougahara."
And things like that.
Just a bit ago, Hoshina-sensei asked me, "Hanekawa, do you know anything about this?"
I don't really know how you and Senjougahara-san got so close,
but I think people are going to start saying even more things like that from now on.
Yeah... they probably will, won't they.
That's a big problem for you. From now on, you'll need to prove that things aren't like that, Araragi-kun.
You shouldn't just let people say bad things about Senjougahara-san,
like how going out with some guy caused her to go bad.
You're absolutely right.
Well anyway, I told him otherwise.
I told him I didn't think it was like that.
Oh... thanks for that.
But do you really think that?
That it's not like that.
Of course. I never lie, after all.
Other than you, I've never heard anyone but liars use that line.
Really? I think there are plenty!
Honestly, I really feel that Senjougahara-san is developing in the right direction.
I don't know if it's thanks to
recovering from her illness, or thanks to you...
But I think that you need to be by
her side to support how she's changing.
You don't talk like a high school student, you know.
Really? I think I'm perfectly normal.
Really?
Speaking of which, I wonder if Hanekawa has someone.
She's the kind of person that's gentle with anyone,
but I wonder if she has that one special person.
Hey, Hanekawa.
What is it?
What is it, Araragi-kun?
Umm... about Doraemon's secret gadgets-
Ouch!
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah... I'm fine...
But...
You're worrying too much.
Hanekawa, this can't be like that time during Golden Week, can it?
Golden Week, the 9 day period between April 29th and May 7th.
Hanekawa!
It hurts!
She was possessed by a cat.
Meddlecat.
Meddlecat?
Yeah.
It's also known as Silver Cat.
But really, Meddlecat is its more customary name.
It's a cat without a tail; one that doesn't leave anything behind.
What do you mean by that, Oshino?
If we're talking in terms of "reality," then I'd say it's a kind of multiple personality disorder.
That's the inner personality of your President manifesting itself.
The black, bad Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Let's call her "Black Hanekawa."
But she's white.
It doesn't matter what's outside, but rather, what's inside.
What's wrong, Araragi-kun? You're more impatient than normal.
Even when you were assaulted by monsters over spring break, you weren't this distracted.
And? How are we going to get Hanekawa back to normal?
I'm telling you, don't worry. I'll explain just how to do it.
Anyway, there's a reason that the black President,
or rather, the Meddlecat, is appearing now.
That reason is likely stress.
Stress?
It's probably an extreme amount of stress, too.
Like the large amount of stress that accumulates over a long period of time.
Araragi-kun, the President isn't under any kind of stress, is she?
It could be love, or studies, or perhaps her family...
Night after night, Black Hanekawa attacked passersby without discrimination.
By doing this, it was attempting to relieve Hanekawa's stress.
One of the Meddlecat's characteristics as an aberration is energy drain.
Like when it often appears in video games, it is the power to absorb strength and energy from people you touch.
Of those who were energy drained, the worst were hospitalized.
Two people were hospitalized.
They were the first, and most serious, victims.
They were also the cause of Hanekawa's stress...
Those were her parents.
Then, on the final day of Golden Week, May 7th...
Hey, human, I've trapped you nyow.
Showing off, trying to follow me around...
I don't really knyow what you're trying to do, but it's pointless, meow.
Until my myaster's stress is completely gone, I won't be going anywhere.
And speaking of which, if that stress is nyot relieved in a year...
Shinobu... no, she didn't yet have the name Shinobu at that time.
One of her characteristics as a vampire is, like the Meddlecat, energy drain.
But to compare a Meddlecat to a vampire... the level of aberration is completely different.
The Meddlecat, which could also be said to be the avatar of Hanekawa's stress,
was drained by Shinobu's energy drain, and disappeared.
Hanekawa's stress was, for the time being, reduced.
Just like that, the problem was solved.
This seems just like that time during Golden Week,
though nothing out of the ordinary is happening.
But...
Hey, Hanekawa!
Really, I'm okay.
We should go... no, the school infirmary's closed by now.
We should go to the hospital.
I said I'm fine. You're blowing this out of proportion.
But you said this has been happening often, lately...
And I'm telling you, you're worrying too much.
You're really a chicken sometimes, Araragi-kun.
But you're...
You really are kind, Araragi-kun.
More importantly, Araragi-kun, have you been trying to understand Senjougahara-san?
It's not enough to just understand, though.
You have to put it into action.
Yeah, I know...
Sorry for always making you worry about it.
It's fine.
Anyway, if you really understand
what I'm saying, Araragi-kun, come on...
What?
Those bloomers and school swimsuit
that you're clutching like treasures...
Perhaps you should at least put them in your bag.
I'm Karen!
I'm Tsukihi!
We've already reached the 11th preview!
It really is the 11th one.
11 is a prime number, right?
It certainly is prime.
What is the definition of a prime number?
A number that is not divisible other than itself
or a positive integer other than one.
Where is that number?
It's a fake number.
Then what's the definition of a prime number?
A positive integer, not a prime number.
It is a number!
A prime number, right?
It's the closing puzzle!
Puzzle?
What's the difference between a puzzle and a quiz?
Puzzles are tricky.
Quizzes are hard!
So hard.
So tricky!
Next time, Tsubasa Cat Part Two!
So, what's the definition of a mantissa?
I don't know.